MERT KARACAM

Senior Software Engineer

CONTACT

+90 (533) 210 92 82

mert.karacamm@gmail.com

Turkey-Istanbul-Sisli

in Linkedin.com/in/mert-karacam

https://github.com/mertkaracamm

SUMMARY

Software engineer with 7+ years of experience in Payment Systems and Financial technology (Fintech). Architectural level experience for digital banking platforms and highly scaled banking systems. Worked as a development lead on many projects while technical lead in an agile nexus framework team. Highly experienced in all aspects of the software development life cycle, especially web applications, data governance, security, and DevOps issues.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE Computer Engineering

Istanbul Technical University (ITU) %100 English 2009 - 2015

High School

Mathematics - Science Branch Kurtulus High School

2005 - 2009

EXPERTISE

- Java (Spring/Spring Boot)
- Primefaces/Java Presantation Layer
- C++/C#
- Oracle/PLSQL
- MSSQL/TSQL
- ETL Tool (SSIS/Informatica)
- DevOps Cycle (Jenkins/TFS, Openshift, Docker)
- Linux, Oracle Weblogic Server
- Weka, Machine Learning

CERTIFICATIONS

Microservices Software Architecture

Udemy

05.2020

DevOps: CI/CD with Jenkins pipelines Udemy

05.2020

Elasticsearch with LogStash and Kibana Udemy

05.2020

Oracle SQL Tuning

Oracle | Bilginc IT Academy

07.2018

Java SE 8 Programming

Oracle 09.2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

Master Expert Developer

Turkcell Technology - Industrial & Financial Solutions | Istanbul | 10.2018 - Present

- Providing credit solutions for corporate and individual customers.
- As a technical lead, being responsible for managing software development processes and determining coding standards for agile squad teams.
- Ensuring the creation of web applications infrastructure and architecture using Java.
- Maintaining discrete repos of web applications as Microservice Architecture in terms of service discovery, load balancing, api gateway, centralized logging.
- Writing SOAP/REST services in accordance with api gateway OAuth2 protocol and JWT-based authentication.
- To prepare the documentation of all modules to provide organizational memory.
- Being the development lead of the **Corporate Assignment Project**, which creates a loan volume of more than 30 million ₺ on average per month (Java, C#).
- Being the development lead of the Online Shopping Lending Project, which is about shopping credits through Paycell and e-commerce companies. (Java,React,C#).
- Being responsible for the data migration project, where a total of 250 million data is moved from the source server to the target server (MSSQL).
- Managing and maintaining financell.com.tr site with a user volume of approximately 3M (Java, React).
- Being responsible for Unit Security Code Architecture in order to manage source code.
- Being responsible for Unit Data Portfolio Architecture in order to manage data governance issues.

Senior Software Developer

YapiKredi Bank – Cards & Payment Systems | Istanbul | 07.2015 – 10.2018

- Working on Pos & Online Applications; CampEngine, POS, Authorization (C++).
- Being responsible for Campaign Applications (C++, C#, Java).
- Managing and maintaining Acquiring, Issuing, Switching applications.
- Providing EMV, VISA, MASTERCARD, BKM regulations.
- SQL queries, Store Procedures with major Relational Databases: Oracle 9i/10g/11g.
- Writing SOAP/REST services in accordance with the api gateway OAuth2 protocol.
- To develop World Loyalty Project, which is about brand points for customers.
- To develop **World Mobile Project,** is a mobile application where customers can participate in campaigns and follow the campaigns they participate in.

Software Developer Intern

ENKA A.Ş Software Development Department | Istanbul | 2014 Turkey Is Bank Information Technology/DBA| Istanbul | 2013

- Working on WCF Services, Windows Forms Applications (ENKA).
- Working on mainframe database systems which is called IMS and DB2(Turkey Is Bank).

PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

Capture the Flag Cyber Security Competition Turkcell 2021

Second Prize / Black Belt Security Master

CXO Awards Turkcell 2021

First Prize / Corporate Assignment Project Third Prize / Banking Conversion Project